european-athletics.org 2013-06-09

# | Privacy Policy

* * *

Welcome to european-athletics.org (the “Website"), operated by the European Athletic Association (EA) (“European Athletics”, “We”, “Our”). European Athletics takes the Website’s users (“User”, “You”, “Yourself”, “Your”) privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about Our Privacy Policy and the ways in which We use Your information before You proceed with use of the Website.

Date of issue of this Privacy Policy: May 2012.

* * *

## International Transfer

YOUR INFORMATION IS PROCESSED IN SWITZERLAND, AND MAY BE STORED AND USED ELSEWHERE DEPENDING ON THE LOCATION OF AFFILIATES, BUSINESS PARTNERS, AND OTHER ENTITIES WHO ARE PERMITTED TO ACCESS SUCH INFORMATION UNDER THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY (AND SUCH LOCATIONS MAY INCLUDE COUNTRIES WHICH MAY NOT AFFORD THE SAME LEVEL OF PROTECTION OF SUCH DATA AS THE COUNTRY FROM WHICH YOU PROVIDED THE INFORMATION). IN SUBMITTING INFORMATION TO US, YOU SPECIFICALLY AGREE TO THAT TRANSFER AND ANY RELATED PURPOSES.

* * *

## The collection of information and how We use it

The main reason why European Athletics collects information is to provide and improve the Website and the services, features and content, to administer Your membership (together, the “Service”) and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Website.

* * *

## The information We collect from You

European Athletics does not collect personal identifying information when you access the Website homepage and browse the Website without disclosing Your personal data except as described in this Privacy Policy or the relevant part of the Website and except cookies (see below under "cookies").

European Athletics collects personal identifying information when You register on the Website, when You use certain products or services on the Website and when You enter promotions, sweepstakes or similar services sponsored by European Athletics or its business partners. European Athletics may also receive personal identifying information from its business partners. When You register, European Athletics asks for Your name, email address, and some other personal information. Once you register with European Athletics and/or sign in to our products or services, You are not anonymous to European Athletics. In case You sign in via Your social network authentication services (Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo account), European Athletics may receive some information from Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo, but You remain solely responsible for Your whole relationship with Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo, including, without limitation, any content on the Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo websites. In case You terminate Your membership with Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo and/or terminate the links between Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo and Our Website, European Athletics will delete all data received from Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo concerning you if you ask European Athletics to do so. You can do so using the same easy way as for the ability to access Your personal identifying information as defined in this Privacy Policy. Further, Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo may require European Athletics to delete data received from Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo APIs in case of violation of their terms. If Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo will disable any links to Our website, European Athletics will delete all your date received through the use of the Facebook/Twitter/LinkedIn/Yahoo APIs, unless it is a basic account information or European Athletics have received explicit consent from You to retain your data. 

* * *

## Automatic Information

European Athletics also automatically receives and records information on Our server logs from Your browser including Your Internet Protocol address (IP address), which identifies Your computer, European Athletics’ cookies information and the page You requested. 

European Athletics uses information collected for four general purposes: for technical administration of the Website, for research and development to achieve and maintain a high service level and for customer information (to customise the content you see, to fulfil your request for certain products and services, to send You newsletters and press releases and to contact You about specials and new products and services).

Aggregate information shall also be used to customise the advertising. In using the Website, You expressly entitle European Athletics to collect and process Your information in particular for such marketing and customisation of the Service. You may always revoke Your consent by deleting Your account.

* * *

## Cookies

European Athletics, like many other websites, may set and access cookies on Your computer. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to Your browser from a website's computer and stored on Your computer's hard drive.  
European Athletics uses its own cookies for number of purposes, mainly to: 

  * access Your information when You "sign in", so that We can provide You with customised content;
  * keep track of preferences You specify while You are using European Athletics’ services;
  * estimate and report Our total audience size and traffic;
  * conduct research and development to improve the Website contents and services and achieve and maintain a high service level.    

European Athletics may allow third parties that are presenting promotions or researching users response to advertisement on some of Our pages to set and access their own cookies on Your computer. Third parties' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies and not this one.

* * *

## Phishing

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to European Athletics. Safeguarding information to help protect You from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request Your credit card information, Your account ID, login password or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.

* * *

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

European Athletics may send information about You to other companies or people when:

a) We have Your consent to share the information; or  
b) We need to share Your information to provide the product or service You have requested; or  
c) We provide the information to companies who work on behalf of European Athletics under confidentiality agreements; or  
d) We respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; or  
e) We believe it is necessary, as determined in Our sole discretion, to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, emergency situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of European Athletics ‘s terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

* * *

## Security

We want You to feel confident about using the Website. For that reason, We have implemented reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure Your information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. However, the Internet is an open system and We cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use Your information for improper purposes.

If You communicate with European Athletics by e-mail, You should note that the secrecy of Internet e-mail is uncertain. By sending sensitive or confidential e-mail messages or information which are not encrypted You accept the risk of such uncertainty and possible lack of confidentiality over the Internet.

* * *

## Your right to access information

You are entitled to see the information held about You. If You wish to do this, please send us an email at office@european-athletics.org. We may require You to provide verification of Your identity and to pay an administration fee to provide a copy of the information we hold. Please note that in certain circumstances We may withhold access to Your information where We have the right to do so under current data protection legislation.

* * *

## Updating/deleting Your information

You may review, correct, update, change or delete Your personal information at any time by accessing Your account on European-athletics.org. We will attempt to accommodate Your request for deletion if We do not have any legal obligation to retain the record. Please send us an email at the following address if you wish to review, correct, update, change or delete Your data : office@european-athletics.org.

* * *

## Links to Other Sites

If any part of the Website links to other websites, those websites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. If You choose to visit an advertiser or click on another third party link, You will be directed to that third party’s website. We do not exercise control over third party websites and therefore recommend You examine the privacy statements posted on these other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing personal information.

* * *

## Our policy towards children

If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal information without their consent, he or she should delete the account (refer to: Updating/deleting Your information). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without such consent, we will delete such information from our files.

* * *

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

This policy may be amended from time to time. If we amend the Privacy Policy in any way we will place an updated version on this page of the Website. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Website.

* * *

## Jurisdiction and applicable law

This Privacy Policy and all matters arising out of or related to this Privacy Policy shall be governed by the substantive laws and principles of Switzerland, without regards to conflicts of laws and principles thereof.  
Any dispute, controversy or claim arising out of or in relation to this Privacy Policy, including the validity, invalidity, breach or termination thereof, shall be decided exclusively by the ordinary courts of the canton Vaud, Switzerland, subject to an appeal to the Swiss Federal Tribunal.

Welcome to european-athletics.org (the “Website"), operated by the European Athletic Association (EA) (“European Athletics”, “We”, “Our”). European Athletics takes the Website’s users (“User”, “You”, “Yourself”, “Your”) privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about Our Privacy Policy and the ways in which We use Your information before You proceed with use of the Website.  
Date of issue of this Privacy Policy: May 2012.
